Bruce Russell Papers
Bruce Russell Papers
- Original drawings
  - By others
    - Pratt, Newton. "Hurricane Babel" (civil rights filibuster), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Pughe, J. S. "Begosh" (bull with football player), Oct 1907; Puck illustration, pen and ink (Oversize 11)
    - Pughe, J. S. Untitled illustration (farmer), 7 Oct 1901; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Pughe, J. S. Untitled illustration (banquet), 16 Sep 1907; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Ray, S. J. "When things get too badly out of hand at home....", undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Roth, Ben. "What this country needs is a good five dollar cigar" (John L. Lewis), 1947; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Russell, Bruce, Jr. Untitled illustration (American eagle), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Schulz, Charles. "Peanuts" strip (Davy Crockett), 27 Jun 1955; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 11)
    - Seibel, Fred O. "Spirit of '43" (wartime shortages), 21 Dec 1943; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Shanks, Bruce. "Egg hunt" (federal budget cuts), 17 Apr 1956; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Shanks, Bruce. "The No. 1 obstacle to peace.", 28 Feb 1957; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Shanks, Bruce. "Thanksgiving '56", 21 Nov 1956; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Shoemaker, Vaughn. "End of the trail?" (Truman), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 11)
    - Shoemaker, Vaughn. Untitled caricature, undated (Oversize 16)
    - Shoemaker, Vaughn. "The unappreciative guest" (F.D.R.'s "Soak the rich" program), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Shuman, Ray. Untitled illustration (café scene), 1931; pen and ink, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Smith, Dorman H. Untitled cartoon (Boulder Dam), undated (Oversize 16)
    - Stampone, John. "This is where we came in" (post-World War II tensions), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Svoboda, V. A. "We should worry about having no turkey.", 1946; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Svoboda, V. A. "The crusader" (food conservation), 1946; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Tashlin, Frank (Tish Tash) "News note - Bruce Russell takes vacation. Tish Tash will pinch-hit for next two weeks.", 19 Apr 1936; color panel (Oversize 16)
    - Taylor, C. J. Untitled illustration, undated; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Thomas, Burt. "Retreating supermen" (soldiers along the front), 1943; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Van Buren, Raeburn. "Abbie an' Slats" strip, 2 May1943; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 11)
    - Vic. Unidentified caricature (man smoking a cigar), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Warren, L.D. "Vest pocket war" (Chiang vs. Mao), 3 Nov 1954; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Werner, Charles G. Untitled cartoon (Congressional legislation), 1944; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Wheeler, "Kate's Kwerie" comic strip (Oversize 16)
    - Willard, Frank. "Mistaken Identity" comic strip, Jan 11 [no year] (Oversize 16)
    - Willard, Frank. "Wild men I have known", 1917; inscribed to A.M. Moore (Oversize 10)
    - Yardley, Moco. "The rewooing of poor Butterfly"(John Foster Dulles and Japan), Mar 1951; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Zimmerman, Eugene (ZIM). Untitled illustration (man on stoop reading calling card), undated; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified. "The Loner" (Defeated Liberalism in Texas), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified. "...as the clock strikes two!" (hobo in a hallway), 1908; pen and ink; possibly by Jay "Ding" Darling (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified. Untitled illustration (crowd of spectators on a street), undated; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified. Untitled illustration (two men with wreaths), undated; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified. "Hope!" (China) [MISSING 3/2/17], 1932; inscribed to Bruce Russell from Leo
    - Unidentified. Untitled cartoon (Demosthenes lecturing the head of NATO), undated; captions in modern Greek and an attached sheet of explanation in French (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified. Untitled illustration from Puck (typist in a tub, huge thermometer with Santa Claus on top), 1910; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Unidentified fragment. Editorial cartoon, "The Hog in the Manger" (municipal spending), undated (Oversize 10)
- Writings
  - Notes on Rollo Rollingstone, circa 1931 (Box 25)
  - Questions for State Department Panel and Pentagon Panel, circa 1963 (Box 25)
Topical index to cartoons
This topical index only covers Russell's original editorial cartoon art. It does not include the editorial cartoon clippings, nor the original editorial cartoon art by other artists.
Adenauer, Konrad R
airline industry/air safety I L T
Algeria Untitled
Austria M
baseball M
black market H
Brown, Pat N R
business E
Butler, Paul Y
Byrd, Richard E. C
California C I R W
campaigns B G I O P
Canada N
Castro, Fidel E
census I
China N P T
citrus industry G
class warfare W
Communism B C E O T W
Congress A S T W Y
crime A L S S T W
Cuba E O
death penalty S
Democratic party B I M Y
dictators T
divorce D
Dollfuss, Engelbert M
drought F
drugs G
education A H R S
Eichmann, Adolf E
Eisenhower, Dwight D. I
employment Untitled
England J M O R
Estes, Billie Sol B C
ethics T
Ethiopia H
Europe J
farmers B F O
fascism F
fire/fire prevention I L O
floods C
Foch, Ferdinand H
football M
Foreign Service W
France B H
gambling N S
Georgia I
Germany B D E U W
Goldberg, Arthur T
Goldwater, Barry O Y
government, cost of F H I R S Y
handicapped D
health care N S
Hiss, Alger P
Hoffa, Jimmy C H NUntitled
holidays A C D H R
Hollywood Bowl A H
home ownership W
Hoover, Herbert C H J K L M N R
Illinois A
income I
India M T
inflation I T
Italy L
Kefauver, Estes I P
Kennedy, John F. C G T
Khrushchev, Nikita A H
kidnaping L
Kuchel, Thomas W
labor C P
Lewis, John L. C
Lindbergh, Charles C
Longworth, Nicholas S
Macmillan, Harold O
Maine M S
March of Dimes S
McCarthy, Joseph R
Menon, V.K. Krishna T
Mexico A
Michigan P
Middle East M
militarism C D F I J L N P
Monroe Doctrine H O
Morse, Wayne W
Mussolini, Benito H
Nazis D U
Nehru, Jawaharlal M
Nevada D
New Deal O
New Hampshire N
newspapers D
Nicaragua O
nuclear power O
nuclear weapons O S T
Obregón Salido, Álvaro A
oil K
Olympics H
peace B Untitled
Philadelphia N
pollution P
population B M
prisons S
Prohibition I S
revolutions T
Rockefeller, John D. O Y
Romney, George P
Roosevelt, Franklin Delano I M P W
Russia A C F P R
science S
Smith, Margaret Chase A
socialism R
South Pole C
space program C
Spain I N S
Stassen, Harold E. N W
Stevenson, Adlai A H P T
strikes J P W
Suez Canal Z
Supreme Court M P T
Taft, Robert A. W
taxes A B C D H M O T U W Y
television E
Tennessee I
Texas S
The Pilgrimage Play (movie) I W
traffic fatalities B C D E I L M N R(1) R(2) T W
treaties A N T
Truman, Harry S. D
U.S. Postal Service D
unemployment I
United Nations F
voting L R
wages G
weather A C F H S W
World War II D E